Dear Gentlemen,

I am an automotive mechanical engineer, graduated at ULBRA in 2012, Studying process engineering and production systems at PUCRS, fluent English skills and intermediate Spanish, which likes to combine its knowledge to practical experiences. As well, I also have plenty of international professional experiences servicing equipment.

I worked for 2 years in product engineering, designing, improving and testing items related to tractors at John Deere Montenegro, being always curious and trying to learn the most about it. On that time, I had the opportunity to do an Internship at John Deere Werke, in Mannheim-Germany, where for 2 months I worked on model updates for the new environmental law specifications in Europe.

Since 2013, I work for Ciber Equipamentos rodoviários (Wirtgen Group) as a technical instructor in the service department, commissioning and servicing road building equipment and asphalt plants. Acquiring knowledge to train service technicians and customers about application, electrical and hydraulic systems, maintenance, and diagnosis. These services and trainings made were in various countries, such as Malaysia, Zambia, Peru, Ivory Coast, Egypt, South Africa, making a good use of my communication skills in English and Spanish.

In July 2016 I have been selected to perform a customer support project in Mexico for 6 months. This project had the objective to improve customer satisfaction, equipment reliability and the dealer development in knowledge, parts market share and support in asphalt plants.

I have availability to travel, and driver's license.

I hope this information is helpful, my resume is attached, containing all further information about myself. I hope my qualifications fulfill the job requirements and will be available to an interview.

Cordially,

Brunno Schulz

Brunno Schulz Rua Francisca Lechner, 152 Porto Alegre, RS, 91180-560 (51) 8584-1991 schulz.brunno@hotmail.com 25 anos

#### Goal

Find a position that I can perform my best, taking the experience acquired through the jobs and studies done in life, applying it in order to help the company grow and succeed.

### **Skill Summary**

- 3 year experience in product support, coordinating technicians, commissioning of new equipment, customer support, project improvement and instructor of technical trainings to dealer technicians and customers.
- 6 months as product support project manager in Mexico.
- 2 year experience in product engineering, new products release, and continuous improvement.
- Ability with 3D CAD software and CAE.
- Fluent English, confirmed by TOEFL results, exchange program in USA, internship in Germany, and several services done in various countries.
- Fluent Spanish skills.
- Intermediate German skills.

# **Academic Background**

- Specialization course (Latu Sensu) in process engineering and production systems-PUCRS- Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil. (2013-2016)
- Bachelor's degree in automotive mechanical engineering ULBRA Canoas, RS, Brazil (2008-2012)

### **Professional Experience**

## 01/2016-Current Ciber Equipamentos Rodoviários

Department: Service, Product Support Function: Technical Support Analyst

Ativities: Support Dealers, technicians and costumers regarding asphalt plants maintenance, repair and application. Coordinating technicians and visiting dealers and customers to improve support and spare parts sales. Evaluation of spare parts stock according to machine population and wear factors.

## 06/2015-12/2016 Ciber Equipamentos Rodoviários

Department: Service, Product Support

Function: Project Manager

Ativities: Teach technicians and customers about application, electrical and hydraulic systems, diagnosis of asphalt plants and compactors. Commissioning of road-building equipment in Brazil and around the globe. Service engineer, solving machine problems during warranty and upon request from customers.

## 04/2013-05/2015 Ciber Equipamentos Rodoviários

Department: Service, Product Support

Function: Technical Instructor

Ativities: Teach technicians and customers about application, electrical and hydraulic systems, diagnosis of asphalt plants and compactors. Commissioning of road-building equipment in Brazil and around the globe. Service engineer, solving machine problems during warranty and upon request from customers.

## 12/2010-12/2012 John Deere Montenegro

Department: Product engineering

Function: Trainee

Ativities: Mechanical projects related to operator station, cost reduction and continuous improvement. Technical drawings, engineering deviations of the area, verification of bill of material comparing to assembly line, Routing check of wiring harness and

hydraulic lines, DPAR and PLRA.

### 01/2012-02/2012 **John Deere Werke- Mannheim, Alemanha**

Department: Project Management

Function: Intern

Ativities: Global John Deere mid tractor line configuration update, specification update for the new environmental law and keep up

with new projects.

#### 04/2010-10/2010 lesa Nissan Veículos

Department: Sales Function: Intern

Ativities: Organization and verification of the new cars, scheduling

and commissioning to the final costumer.

### **Courses and Training**

- Certified technician in Ciber asphalt plants, operation, maintenance and repair.
- Certified technician in Hamm compactors, operation, maintenance and repair.
- PTC ProEngineer Course Modeling, Drawing, Sheet metal and piping- 2011
- SAP engineering utilities course
- PTC Windchill Course
- JD&T Intermediate course

- Junior Achievement Mini Business Colégio Concórdia 2006
- Computer assembly and maintenance Senac 2005
- CERT (Community Emergency Response Team) course USA 2007
- High school exchange program at Kansas, USA

#### **Additional Information**

- 1st SAE Brazil Symposium of lean manufacturing participant, 2010
- 1st SAE Brazil Symposium of agricultural machines—2012.
- TOEFL test score: 105 points ,IBT
- 4th Place at "heart of the plains league", chemistry, Kansas, USA
- State honorable mention, Chemistry, Kansas, USA
- Fuel efficiency college marathon participant, São Paulo, Brazil, 2008
- Community service Attica, Kansas, USA 2006-2007
- Basketball athlete GNU, Attica High School, Sogipa
- NAIAS (North Amercian International Auto Show) participant Detroit,2011
- Knowledge of Microsoft Office and Internet Explorer
- Knowledge in CAD, Solid Edge and PRO-E
- Knowledge in production lines and quality tools
- Knowledge in power hydraulic systems and industrial electrics.